Inventory of the Robert Morton Hughes Papers 1715-1933
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Autograph Collection, 1750-1933. (Box-folder 2:1-5)
  - Autograph Collection, P-T, 1753-1924., 26 items. (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Elizabeth M. Sewell, n.p., to Miss [?] Rowland, n.p., 15 April n.y., 2 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Is away from home but hopes to see Miss Rowland on her return.
    - Roger Sherman and Israel Baldwin, Committee, lay out 5 1/2 acres in the Township of New Milford, [Connecticut] for Ann Gunn, Ruth Gunn, and Jane Gunn, daughters of Nathan Gunn, late of New Milford, deceased, being land wanting in a former division between Enos Camp and said Nathan Gunn, 16 March 1753., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Mrs. L. Huntley Sigourney, no date., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Signature. C.S.
    - Sillorin[?], au Conservatoire du Arts et Metiers, to [?], 15 January 1861., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Response concerning a possible weapon testing; received the letter through the U.S. embassy; news of friend's suicide attempt; offers to help in any way possible [with the new weapon].
    - E. Kirby Smith, Louisville, [Kentucky], to [?], 7 October [18]66., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Expansion of the Louisville and Nashville Railroad in Eastern Kentucky.
    - Instructions to the jury drawn by Governor William Smith in the trial of the suit of the United States vs. William Smith, 22 May 1879., 1 page. AD. (Box-folder 2:4)
      The suit concerned Virginia funds expended by Smith just previous to the fall of the Virginia government in 1865.
    - Robert Southey, Keswick, [England], to Edward Maxon, [London, England?], 18 July 1836., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Letter to his publisher regarding literary matters.
    - George Stoneman, Maj. Gen., U.S., Knoxville, Tennessee, 3 January 1866., 1 page. Cy. of D. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Certification that on 8 April 1865 Supplies were taken from A. Staples of Patrick C[ourt] H[ouse], Virginia, by the Federal forces.
    - Joseph Story, Washington, [D.C.], to The Rev. [William B.] Sprague, West Springfield, Massachusetts, 13 March 1829., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Sends autographs of the judges of the Supreme Court and a copy of his centennial discourse.
    - Alex[ander] H. H. Stuart, Staunton, Virginia, to Luther H. Read, Hampton, Virginia, 28 January 1841., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Testimonial letter regarding Joseph Segar who is seeking office of charge d'affairs to Texas.
    - Booth Tarkington, Indianapolis, [Indiana], to Miss Helena Marsh, c/o New York Evening Post, New York City, [New York], 10 January 1924., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Concerns purchase of film rights to "The Two Vanrevels".
    - Bayard Taylor, Kennett Square, Pennsylvania, to "Dear Sir," n.p., 3 October 1863., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Gives his terms for delivering lectures.
    - Litt[let]on W. Tazewell, Washington, [D.C.], to William W. Sharp, Norfolk, Virginia, 7 February 1831., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Concerns the legal aspects of a case in which Sharp is involved.
    - Sam[ue]l L. Clemens, Hartford, [Connecticut], to Geo[rge] S. Merrill, n.p., 8 February 1877., 2 pages. LS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Regrets being unable to attend the annual re-union of the Massachusetts Press Association.
  - Autograph Collection, V-Z and Miscellaneous, 1792-1915., 16 items. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - M. Van Buren, n.p., to the Rev. Mr. [William B.] Sprague, n.p., 17 August 1830., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Will take charge of the parcel Sprague is sending Dr. Lawrie.
    - Pedro Del Villar, General Headquarters Military Health Corps Mesa Section, Mexico, to General Gab[rie]l Valencia, n.p., 4 January 1826 [sic][1836]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Concerned with the supply of medical personnel; marching information. In Spanish.
    - John R. Voorhis, Board of Elections, New York, [New York], to Miss [?] Marsh, n.p., 31 May 1924., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Concerns a letter from the New York Times he had misplaced.
    - Geo[rge] Walton, Augusta, [Georgia], to Isaac Watkins, Knoxville, Tennessee, 12 September 1800., 2 pages. LS. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Discusses and gives approval as a "Commissioner of the state" to Isaac Watkins and Colonel Whitley to construct a road, to be built through the "Cherokee country to the highest navigation of the Savannah River."
      Including a Acy of D of an extract from Judge [George] Walton, n.p., 28 April 1800, to the Grand Jury of Wilkes County, [Ga.], concerning his enquiries regarding the best routes for roads from the Tennessee River into Georgia. 2 pages.
    - G. Washington, Mount Vernon, [Virginia], to James Madison, Jun[io]r, n.p., 20 May 1792., 6 pages. ACy of ALS. (Box-folder 2:5)
      Political discussion. [Reproduced from original in possession of J.C. McGuire, Washington, D.C.].
    - Receipt from Capt. J. C. McDonald of Tazewell Troop, 3 September 1861., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:5)
      For 95 prisoners, and "five citizens who are suspicious persons", signed by Brig. Gen. Jo[h]n H. Winder.
    - Owen Wister, Sherwood Inn, Old Point Comfort, Virginia, to Miss [?] Smith, n.p., 18 March 1911., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder xx)
      Will send The Virginian for the Williamsburg Library. His Washington is the "apple of its author's eye."
    - Outline of a speech on the current political situation delivered in Abingdon, Virginia, 1860., 2 pages. AMS. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Engraving of G. P. R. James (Baden: Whitechurch, 1846), bearing James' signature., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - [Visiting card?] of first Japanese Commission to the U.S., 1 page. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Cover page [?] for a receipt and inventory for a parcel of property of a group known as the "Capresada," being part of the "Upper Echelon" of the society, 14 March 1847., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 2:5)
      In Spanish.
    - Confederate money, one Confederate stamp, a poem on the "Lost Cause," and one piece of Continental currency., 33 items. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Ticket No. 26185 for the Louisiana State Lottery Co., drawing held in New Orleans, [Louisiana], 14 April 1891., 1 page. PD. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Souvenir menu of a dinner given by the Bar of the Supreme Court of the United States in honor of Mr. Justice John Marshall Harlan, (1833-1911). [Contains Ph and Cy of signature of John M. Harlan on cover]. 9 December 1902., 2 pages. PM. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Memorial proclamation made by the Governor of Virginia, William Hodges Mann, (1843-1927), authorizing a day of mourning, 1 July 1910, for John Warwick Daniel, (1842-1910), Confederate soldier, Senator, and statesman. [Contains Ph and Cy of Signature of John Warwick Daniel], 30 June 1910., 3 pages. PM. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - The Collector, A magazine for Autograph and Historical Collectors. New York, [New York], Vol. XXIX, No. 2; Whole No. 323, December 1915., 12 pages. PM. (Box-folder 2:5)